CONTACT ME AT

(514) 577 0827

meining.cheng@gmail.com

www.meiningcheng.com

in Meining Cheng

Meining2020

SKILLS SUMMARY

HTML5 CSS3 Sass

JavaScript (ES6+) jQuery React

Responsive Design Accessibility

Firebase RESTful APIs

Version Control Git & Git Hub

Group Programming Code Review

Java Python

Project Management

Problem Solving & Analysis

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

Juno College of Technology

Web Development Immersive Bootcamp | Apr - Jun 2021 JavaScript course | Feb - Apr 2021 Web Development course | Nov - Dec 2020

McGill University

Master of Science, Food Science | Jan 2017 - Oct 2018

University of Manitoba

Bachelor of Science, Food Science | Jan 2015 - Feb 2017 (Graduated with Distinction)

MEINING CHENG

WEB DEVELOPER

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am an enthusiastic Web Developer with a passion for building engaging, accessible and responsive websites and apps. My experience working as a Quality Assurance manager in faced-paced manufacturing industries cultivated my abilities to make sound and meticulous decisions as well as handle complex tasks synchronously.

PROJECTS

Foodie's Cookbook (view <u>live | repo</u>)

React | Firebase | API | JavaScript | HTML | CSS

- A react based app which allows users to enter keyword to search food recipes and filter results based on diet type using EDMAN API
- Used Firebase as a real-time database to allow users to save recipes

TMDB Movie Fun (view live | repo)

JavaScript | API | Pair Programming | HTML | Sass

- A movie discover app that allows users to search movies by titles and genres, and obtain detailed information about the movie and cast.
- Collaborative coding project

WORK EXPERIENCE

Quality Compliance Manager

NutraLab Canada Corp. | Nov 2020 - Mar 2021

- Supervised a team of 6 Quality Technicians and trained 75 plant employees on Good Manufacturing Practices
- Liaised between customers, sales, engineering and manufacturing to resolve customer complaints
- Directed about 100 quality-compliant products release per month
- Led 3rd party certification and audit programs

QA/QC Associate

NutraLab Canada Corp. | Jan 2019 - Nov 2020

- Performed in-process inspection to ensure manufacturing instructions and product specifications are followed
- Analyzed product safety and quality data to prepare daily reports for leadership
- · Maintained and updated quality documentations